<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Blog by Srinath Muskula]]></title><description><![CDATA[Engineer, writing about topics related to technology]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 05:12:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Creating My Blog Using Gatsby-React]]></title><description><![CDATA[I will guide you how to create your blog in using gatsby-react and publish posts with very less effort and use markdown, git or AWS S3 to host blog.]]></description><link>undefined/posts/creating-my-blog-using-gatsby-react/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">undefined/posts/creating-my-blog-using-gatsby-react/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 13:10:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have been learning about different ways to host my blog. Easiest and quick way was to use CMS like Wordpress, this requires a server. Wordpress has lot of features and add-ons to use. For me blog is mostly static posts, you don’t need server to host a static site. Just waste of resources. I started looking at famous static site generators like Hugo, Hexo, Jekyll, Pelican. Then I found Gatsby, it’s a React based static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will guide you with below steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up Gatsby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding a theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a new post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push blog to GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host blog on GitHub Pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirect GitHub Pages to a custom domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;https://gatsbyjs.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Gatsby on you local machine, you can use existing starters for quickstart or build website from scratch. I used lumen starter from gatsby central and modified it a little.
Watch this 4 hour &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8t0vNu2fCCM&quot;&gt;bootcamp lesson&lt;/a&gt; by Andrew Mead to understand gatsby, react.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have developed your gatsby site. Head over to github and create a repository as gitusername.github.io  and push your site code to this repo. Optionally you can add your custom domain name to the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need help in creating your gatsby site contact me.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>